welcome to today's inventory planner
webinar on
open to buy planning so open to buy is a
hot topic it's a frequently asked
question
with merchants that we commonly work
with for demand forecasting
and planning what items to purchase for
your store
open to buy can be really great for
stores that have a lot of seasonality
to your buying stores that are
constantly introducing a lot of new
products so you don't have sales history
on specific
items but more at a category level and
it can also be good for stores that are
growing rapidly so have
very aggressive revenue goals and open
to buy can help with
reaching those goals so with that quick
introduction i'm going to turn it over
to basil who will go through the details
on how you can set up an open to buy
plan in
inventory planner yes awesome
thank you jill i see some familiar uh
some familiar names in here thank you
for joining us today
uh we're excited we have made some
exciting updates that you will be the
first to know about open to buy
um so let's go ahead and just jump right
in we don't have as like a a super
strict
outline for today because open to buy is
meant to be a little squishy it's
catered to what is going on with your
business and it's going to be a little
different for everyone so let's just
kind of walk through it
all right i'm going to go ahead and
share my screen we can just start taking
a look
all right so first and foremost what we
did is we put up a poll for you uh we're
curious to know how familiar you are
with open to buy
um i i do know like i said i have spoken
to several people
on from from that are on this call some
are are very experienced with it
some less some are brand new um
so okay cool
awesome great to see this lifetime
feedback and we're gonna have a few
different polls that pop up in here just
helps us to get a an understanding of
how everybody's business works
and and different kinds of improvements
we need to make
um cool looks like we have some brand
brand new
users that's helpful to know it's going
to change a little bit of the way that
we talk
about it today great all right
so you can see my screen i hope
so what i'm gonna do here i'm just gonna
go ahead
and so we opened up our demo store and
if when you log into our demo store you
can access
our demo store anytime uh from
from our home page so if you were to go
to the inventory planner
dot com to the demo store up here
you're gonna find it um i also have it
already open over here so
hero of course you start in our overview
page and you're gonna notice that open
device section
you might be wondering to yourself what
is this so open to buy
really it's a more advanced feature of
inventory planner
but i like to think of it as the first
step in the
greater workflow and yes also as you
have questions
as you go along please feel free to drop
them there in the chat
jill just sent a note over there so you
should have seen a notification so if
any of the questions come up
so i like to think of it as a first step
in the sense that
open to buy really is about it's about
cash flow planning
it's about planning at a high level
you're purchasing budgets if
and then we can take that information to
drill into our forecasting and
replenishment analysis
so it's a really good place to first get
a sense what do we actually have
open to buy in any given month based on
a variety of factors
including and most importantly our
planned revenue goals for the upcoming
months
and our ideal stock cover going in to
all of those months
all right so here we are in open to buy
you're going to notice we have our
locations filter just as we usually do
we can create plans at a variety of
levels whether we go into a specific
warehouse
or if we look at our combined warehouse
that's aggregating
all of our locations together all right
now we can create different plans and we
can also
do a top-down or a bottom-up plan now i
would always suggest starting with a
bottom-up plan
and the reason i say that is because the
behavior you're gonna notice in open to
buy
at the with the bottom-up method
it's it's the same when you do a
top-down or a top-down method
except we just do it if you do if you
were to enter for example planned
revenue goals
and forward cover goals at a top level
we're literally just doing it for every
single
category or subsection that we're
looking at so it's the same idea this is
when you do it at top down it's just
repeating the behavior for everyone
below it
so really to demonstrate the behavior i
do recommend starting at the bottom of
plan
now for our proficient and somewhat
proficient otb
users we have a very exciting update all
right so what i'm going to do here i'm
going to create a new plan
and you're going to notice something
pretty exciting here
now we can do open to buy by vendor
and by brand as well as category this is
a con this is a frequent request we've
got
uh we can signal that this get the
confetti going jill i'm sure so we'll
get we'll get the confetti going here
shortly
um so what we're curious to know because
we have seen this question so often
we're curious how do you plan your
inventory buying
uh historically you've only had this
available by category
vendor and brand are are new so um
definitely encourage everybody to jump
in with these features let us know how
it's working
we've done quite a bit of testing so far
and we're feeling pretty good about it
all right so okay wow yeah we have a lot
i've been hearing a lot that by vendor
so very excited to
to see that we've added this feature and
i hope that this is going to help you
out
all right so i'm going to do it in here
by category because that's sort of the
baseline
it's going to be the same idea however
we do it right
now i'm going to say we're going to call
this ip test
i'm going to go ahead and create this
plan so it starts to cook you can always
notice that purple line here towards the
top
all right and then um so it's gonna
we're gonna create that plan and then
you're gonna notice
so we're showing all the individual
categories
your categories stem generally from the
product type in your store now you can
always check
also from our home page if you click on
the integrations tab
what kind of attributes we pull from
your system
so for a lot of you know shopify stores
amazon a lot of it's
generally going to be tied to some kind
of product
type so we can see category product type
we give you a little info bubble here
um so you're going to see just a little
more information about how we kind of
determine what a category is
so we started the new plan here's my iep
test
we're doing the bottom up plan i'm in my
combined warehouse today
all right now first thing i want to do
is i want to go down to my actions
button at the bottom
and i just want to make sure that i'm
only looking at relevant categories
to my plan right so i can get a quick
idea of
what's in stock or what's not now we've
had folks that have a lot of categories
or a lot of brands a lot of vendors
we did add a filter here a little select
all deselect all option here
so if you want to selectively turn it
off and turn some categories on
you certainly can do that let's do it
that way these are the ones where i have
some
decent stock some decent information to
work with so i'm going to go ahead and
apply
and now basically we're going to plan by
the categories that are in that category
organizer and those are the ones that
are going to roll back up to the top
for our when we look at our total level
all right
sometimes we see unknown categories or
maybe like a catch
all returns category gift cards that
type of
that type of thing so definitely just
it's it's a good part of the cleanup
process just to
get some of that out of there all right
so that's a key step
the next thing we have to do is to is to
input our planned
revenue goals okay there's a couple ways
we can do it
we can well of course we can just
manually enter our goals if we want
right or we can use actions
we could seed it in the prior year
now what this would mean is just
essentially i'm going to actually
click like cancel that real quick and
you're going to notice that gear icon
it's what we generally use throughout
replenishment reporting etc to add
columns
in your tables well and open to buy
we're adding rows
right so we could for example see our
actual revenue last year
we could even see it two years ago maybe
we were just trying to get an idea now
our demo store doesn't have two years of
history
so let's just work with last year but
you're gonna see last year metrics and
then two years ago metrics that you can
add in here
as a reference as you go along but this
kind of gives me an idea
here's my plan reven or my actual
revenue last year so if i want to seed
my revenue from the prior year a zero
percent
adjustment this is always a little
tricky zero is flat
to prior year you want a ten percent
increase you put ten not a hundred ten
so let's say we're going to do a ten
percent increase on revenue
so we seated in that planned revenue you
can notice it's 10
higher from the prior year so it's a key
first step
now you could also seed it in from your
forecast
if you were to do that where does it
come from
okay so you'll notice the edit forecast
section
you've probably played around in here
before i just opened it in a new tab
just a quick reminder on replenishment
forecasting
um generally we're coming up with your
you know we're using your forecast
method and settings we're determining
your forecast
by variant and we can aggregate it in
different ways
and you can always come to edit
forecasts as a place to make some
adjustments maybe you have specific
promotions we have to consider well we
can aggregate and edit forecasts so if
you're
ever curious if you're trying to seed
your revenue from your forecast you
could come to edit forecast
i would roll it up to the category level
we're going to add up all the individual
sales
the past sales the forecasted sales and
then we're also going to determine the
forecast revenue
so that's where you'd see these values
these forecast revenue values these
would be the ones you'd be seeding into
your open to buy plan
i decided to do it off of last year like
i said usually open divides
i i like to think of it as the first
place to go and then we take that
information and we could actually
seed the planned revenue from open to
buy
into edit forecast to make an actionable
plan for purchasing so that's the way
that i actually prefer to do it is use
the information here
and seat it actually into the forecast
we'll walk back through that
so so far i'm just starting i'm like you
know we've been 10 above year over year
and i believe that this is going to
continue on
so this is what's making up our planned
revenue goals all right so let's keep
going
now when we think of when you look at
all the numbers in here
one really important thing to consider
is that we're looking
at information at retail value
okay we have to do this as an
apples-to-apples comparison
this is all an algorithm for every month
we're getting a snapshot
what is currently in stock so today is
november 11th
so when you see that opening stock
figure here again this is the ladies
category
remember for ladies we have how many
variants do we have
we have plenty of with 45 variants and
ladies
so those are the ones that we're looking
at when we take up the the opening stock
essentially what the stock position was
for every variant in the ladies category
as of november 1st
when we take the the individual stock
times the retail price of that day this
is what the stock added up to
okay against that retail value so that's
the first piece
is saying what did it look like november
1st and then we also needed to get a
snapshot of
what was either received
in the month of november so far or what
is currently on
order again at retail value we could
separate it out here we've grouped it
together
you can always go up to that gear icon
maybe you're trying to get a sense
hey wait what do i have on order how's
this coming through
so we could say what's on order or
what's coming from receipts
my case here it looks like everything is
on order these would be
units or this would be what's on order
currently
to arrive during the month of november
if i wanted to compare this
i could always go to reports delivery
schedule that's a really useful one
and then if you're trying to find
received information good receive note
so you can kind of compare it or to open
delivery schedule as an example
say we look at this in our case by
category since that's how we're
developing our open to buy plan
ladies here is what's scheduled to
arrive in the month of november at
retail
versus cost versus units of course if i
go into purchase orders and start to
dive in
and see what's going what is exactly
which pos are these attached to
or we could always you could dig into
the variants and kind of get a deeper
sense of what's coming and when
what's useful about this report is you
can even drill in by week
so you can go by month or by week in
this particular report
so let's pop back over to open to buy
all right so we've inputted our planned
revenue
we know how we got our opening stock how
we planned our purchases
all that's there all right so now
what we're going to do essentially say
all right if we open our stock
297 000 in retail for ladies
and we have another 65 000 in retail
expected to land during the month of
november so essentially that's our
position
as of you know for the month of november
we have roughly 350 000
to work with to support whatever's
happening this month
now our planned revenue is is
quite high right when we look at what
how it's been last year
you know we we're pretty short so that's
the first thing that's going to happen
here
is we're going to say we're going to
we're going to deduct out the planned
revenue for the for the month we know
this is what we're planning to sell
and we're going to get a snapshot of
that so what's what do we have
what is expect and then what is expected
to sell
so that that is all key that essentially
that's once we kind of take that
that that that zeros us out
essentially and then what's what's going
to be left to buy is going to be
highly driven off of of
our upcoming goals so really what we
need to do
notice we're actually we are
incorporating the back orders you're
going to see this in a moment
so what does this mean well let's
look at december and what we really need
to think about is how do we want to
enter the month of december let's say i
want to i want to enter december
i want it to cover me through december
and january
because the holidays production gets
slow whatever that might be
so i want to make sure i have at least
two months worth going into the month of
december
once we get into the month of january
i'm just gonna i'm gonna bring it down
say a month and a half because i just
wanna at that point i want enough to
cover me through january part of
february
and just like kind of slowly trickle
this out all right let's
we'll maintain a one and a half and then
we'll kind of eventually just bring it
down to one
month all right now let's save that
let's see you're gonna notice some
numbers change
all right what we did here we told the
system
how we want things to look by december
1st i want to enter
the month of december with enough to
cover me
through december and january so that's
why we
we want to enter december with about a
little over 1.2 million would make sure
that we could
cover ourselves for two months so now we
can go
back to november what the system is
telling us
is okay you know based on what we have
in stock what we have coming
based on some heavy sales that are
actually going to push us into a back
order
we need to also buy an additional 1.5
million
to cover the back orders and to make
sure that we get
into the month of november with 1.26
million
that would ensure that we can cover
earnings through december and january
all right so and it'll be the same
repeated behavior the next month might
make even more sense without the back
order piece so
okay we entered december 1.26 million
we're good for a couple months but we
also
we noticed we still also have some
purchases coming
again this is what's scheduled to arrive
in that month
now when we think about open to buy this
is something that we get asked quite
often this
this open to buy figure this you should
think of this really as what should be
received
in the month of november so that we can
set ourselves up for
the month of december so you're open to
buy recommendation
it's really a recommendation on what
should be received purchased
and received ideally within that month
so if you have longer
lead times you know you might need to
actually look at your open to buy
let's say we're planning some purchases
that would land more around february
well we can develop some goals and then
kind of add together our open supply to
get a sense of
okay what do we need to get in here by
january or by february
all right so let's kind of walk through
december 1.26 million
good you know we bought all this in
november we set ourselves up
we see we have some purchases coming not
much we have about 633 000 that we're
going to sell
once we factor all of that into
consideration
subtract that out if we buy
so this is what notice it's not so we
okay
yeah we but we have 1.26 million we we
purchased another 8 000 or so so that's
about
you know a little a little higher than
this and then essentially what we're
saying is
you still need to buy an additional 289
000 so that we can enter january
in a way that means our goal with that
in mind
this would get us to 934. so if i were
to see if i were to say
one here what are you going to notice
the open divide goes down to zero
our closing stocks is six forty five
thousand because we just
we just need just enough in january and
notice actually that number is it
actually rounded up
a little bit well we already have
purchases coming in january
so it's kind of saying all right you
know sure you put you want two months
going into december here's what you need
to buy no
in november to get it done and then even
if you don't buy
anything else because of some existing
pos we have scheduled to arrive in
january
you're technically go you know even
though i said one you have to be a
little
overstocked it's just the nature of it
because we already have those po sitting
out there
all right let's say i want to go take it
back to 1.5 that feels pretty good to me
so cool i have my open to buy plan and
then
from here you know again everything so
far has been at retail value
so what we could do at this point to say
great we know what we need to buy in
november or december
and then we just input our margin say my
margins
65 you just put 65
or or maybe it could be different by a
month right maybe it's 62 in this month
68 here whatever it might be your margin
is ultimately what's going to drive it
down to cost
so everything was at retail value up
until this point and we converted to
cost
using the margin now we could go even
further with that
if i click on the columns here and if i
were to add
average price this would be average
selling price
if we enter that information it also
allows us to calculate
open to buy eight units so let's say
generally in the ladies category my
average price
i'm usually selling my my ladies items
for about 30
or so so if we were to set it up this
way then that would give us
an open to buy the units calculation so
that's how we can back into either cost
or units but we're always going to plan
at retail
now especially seasonal businesses of
course we have to we have to take into
consideration
markdowns it tends to be a pretty key
part
i'm going to reset my rows because i
have a lot of information that was in
there
so we're kind of back to where we were
all right so
cool we have our open to buy unless i'm
going to add in my markdowns
joe and i had a cool conversation the
other day i wanted to kind of put in
perspective how to think about markdowns
uh we'd love actually to hear uh from
you about
how you plan markdowns in your business
um so we so we can kind of get a better
understanding of
of how this all works as part of the
process but the way that we like to
think about it
so really like let's say you're buying
like for for your
for your winter season okay right now
october november december you have a
certain set of products
you're gonna switch that over in the new
year and you're gonna get some different
products
well the reality is some of those old
products today
just aren't going to be worth the same
amount heading into the new year
so that's where we can consider
markdowns it's going to
you really think of markdowns as an
adjustment against
the retail value of your goods let's say
by the time we get to january
we you know all that stuff that we had
november december
sure it was worth a lot more and those
in that q4 period
but if it didn't really sell the way
that we intended and our coverage was a
little too high
now we're going into january and we're
we're going to be sitting on all this
extra product
so planned revenue this is really it's
it's it's your it's your
it's your revenue at your at your retail
price
okay but markdown should be should
consider
the actual price sold and then be that
difference between the retail price and
the actual selling price
so we're going to include all of that as
part of this so we're going to actually
mark down 200 000
you're going to notice it's going to
actually make us buy more because the
reality is
our stock is worth less and if we want
to maintain these plan revenue goals we
have to sell a higher volume at a lower
price to get it done
so the higher our markdowns are going to
be the higher
our open to buy is also going to be to
offset that and make sure that we
purchase enough
to maintain our plan revenue all right
that's the that is the demonstration for
a specific
category i'll show you at the top down
level um i do i see that we have some
questions
uh is there anything we should answer
live or are we yeah a couple
a couple things um one just a quick
recap somebody was asking where to find
the option to select by
category vendor brand so that's going to
be at the bottom of the page there where
you see new plan
and so that'll pop up with with that
drop down
there awesome thank you for showing that
and then
the next question mackenzie is asking
can you alter the time it takes for
merchandise to come in
for a vendor in otb they have several
international vendors so they have a
longer lead time eight to 12 weeks
on production orders so um bazel do you
want to talk through that and kind of
thinking about the the expected time
there expected arrival date
yeah no that's a good question um and i
see we also have a question
aiden i know that's something you and i
have talked about a bit uh you know
uh for for our for this example
you know i know aiden has purchases that
she can't even purchase she can't have
those goods arrive until next i think it
was march or april or may
but we have to factor in like we have
you know there's all these goods coming
in the meantime
and and there's a certain flow to that
stock but we can't actually take action
until what happens in may so we still
have to understand the picture between
now and then
we're still generating all these open to
buy recommendations but we can't cash in
on it
so really the answer unfortunately
currently
you cannot factor in lead time directly
in open to buy
the way you need to kind of think about
it you would be able to put in
your goals say like ideally we would be
yeah let's say we just want to maintain
one and a half months at any given time
all right
but maybe i can't i just can't get it i
can't get the stock until let's say
next april well then we would add
together
because ideally this is everything we
need to buy and be received in these
months
to support the sales that we're seeing
so it's going to
it's going to be and it's going to be
different by business i think that's
what part of what complicates this is we
don't know
if you accept back orders if that's lost
revenue there's a lot of implications
there
right so in this case if we do accept
back orders then
it gives us a sense of you know
especially especially if we already have
pos that are out there and we can see
what's scheduled to arrive in these
upcoming months we're already
considering it
so we're going to see like how do you
enter these different months
what's already coming and then what's
the plan revenue for these so we can get
a sense of what
what the end of the each month is going
to look like and what else the ideally
should be purchased to support it
um i know in the case of aiden in
particular we found that
yeah we have all these goods that are
coming between now and the spring
but there's also it's just it's just not
enough so there's going to be back
orders and we also need to factor that
in as part of what we purchased to come
by april or may so for that we would
just
add up all of this open to buy say like
i can't get it till april yeah well i
would i would actually i would add all
of this together
to figure out this this is actually what
i'm going to buy for ladies to arrive in
the month of april
above and beyond everything i have and
purchase here's i have to buy this much
extra it'll land in april and it would
offset any kind of backorders everything
that i've accrued
so we have to back into essentially
that's how you have to consider the lead
time
if it's let's say if it's generally a
60-day lead time or something right
then you could think of you know let's
say like
um so january is a good example
we want this much to arrive in the month
of january
and so we have to purchase it now right
so if we place that purchase now to
arrive in the month of january
um maybe we want to factor in what
ideally should arrive in this month
maybe we say we want three months of
coverage for december
but it's not actually critical that it's
here by december 1st
we can still get that open to buy a
recommendation to say cool here's what
we would need to support it
maybe you can't get here until december
15th or january 10th whatever it might
be
it still gives you that recommendation
to say if you
ideally were to enter december with
three months this is what that would
look like
um so you could you could use that as a
way as well
is that does that help to answer that
question joe was that pretty clear
yep yep i think we got it there so good
all right yeah and we do hope that um
especially now that we have open to buy
by vendor you know it's it's an ongoing
conversation
we want to think about how lead time
should be considered
um this is this is an ever evolving part
of the system
and there are some new exciting features
in here we are certainly looking to
improve
uh but it does get complex different
variants have different lead times
vendors sometimes have different lead
times by item so there's i think it's
just there's there are a number of
assumptions
when we consider that uh along with the
fact that
not everybody handles back orders
different and it doesn't impact
everybody's business the same
uh but yeah so that's that's that piece
there um
okay is that on the question so far yep
i think that covers the questions uh
so far so you're good cool yeah so
that's
that can be a little tricky but all very
very good questions
what i'm going to do is i'm going to
actually go now to a top-down plan now
you can switch between them at any point
now you'll notice that i mean there's
some numbers in here that are already
happening at the total level
we're taking we're taking the values
from the categories we're aggregating
back up here at the total level
now if you want to plan at a total level
we're going to do everything we just did
for the ladies category
at the total level so it's just you know
we enter it there and it's just going to
try to repeat the behavior for every
single category
all right so what i mean by that is
let's say like at a total level here's
our planned revenue goals all this feels
pretty good
i entered it you know i this is an
interesting example because i already
put in three months for december so
we're probably going to see
some overstock if i try to do something
here right
if i were to try to put 1.5 for december
it's not even going to be possible
because of
everything that's already reflected by
category is already above that
it's going to automatically recalculate
for some overstock
so what happens when we yeah let's try
to do it a total same way we did ladies
let's say we try to do 1.5 across the
board
and then we save that in so it's going
to try to repeat that behavior for every
category
actually in this case we only only had
one uh
overstock issue and we said it's it here
in accessories
for the month of december the issue is
we're already at 1.95
uh coverage for months in the month of
december we can't
set it to 1.5 the lowest it could go
without buying anything is going to be
1.5
so let's scroll down to accessories or
sorry
it recalculates my december because i
told to one point five eleven i put in
one point five
it recalculated to one point five eleven
the reason we can scroll down to
accessories
and let's look at the behavior our
planned revenue it's ten percent higher
than prior year all but just
exactly like we looked at opening stock
as november as of november 1st
we have nothing on order but we see you
know here's what's opening in stock and
the planned revenue
doing nothing here's how we end november
000 we enter december with 62 000.
well that's enough to cover us already
for more than a month and a half
so without doing anything we're
overstocked there so we're saying don't
don't buy anything else in november even
so you're going to enter the month of
december with 1.95
now the categories where we could set it
to 1.5
we did and we gave you an open to buy
recommendation for
for uh for november so we're still we're
going to do it where we can
where we cannot it will calculate over
stock and so generally it's
when you plan at a total level that's
why you're going to see these
recalculations
because it's going to say oh we can't
even we can't we can't actually go that
low
if i were to go even lower so i want to
keep it really lean i would ideally be
just one month of cover at any given
time we're going to get plenty of
overstock errors i'm sure
because i don't know still not quite
that much
yeah it will try to repeat that behavior
for every single category
this one okay so just recalculated to
1.023
um you know the lower i kind of try to
do that the more we're going to notice
overstock issues
and it would have to do some
recalculations i can even try to go
lower 0.5
for example we'll always get that
summary of the overstock errors
uh which categories are impacted yeah so
here's another one here
you know here's here's what happened
when we tried to look at the month of
november we couldn't set it to 0.5 and
it's because dresses
already overstocked bags already
overstocked accessories exactly like we
talked about
so if we try to repeat that behavior for
every month it's going to say okay
actually
it's going to recalculate no matter what
at 0.645
we could do it for ladies it gave us the
recommendation
go down a little further did it do it
for bags it did not do it for bags
because we're
we would already be overstocked doing
nothing right
so that's how that's going to work so
just that's why i say it's generally i
mean it's better to do with the bottom
up plan because you could do
specific categories specific vendors
specific brands
um it's it's a useful kind of strategy
there
um was there another question that
popped up yeah we do have an interesting
question here so ian is asking
open to buy assumes that we're buying
finished products
what if we're buying something that will
be combined into a final finished
product so
we're looking at assemblies plus open to
buy
ian i think you fill out the bingo card
on all the most complex situations there
oh planning that's a doozy so
i think i think ian and aiden need to be
need to be buddies actually because this
will form a support group for you guys
yeah that's just the start he says
um yeah this is this is something we ran
into recently
and um we found that like when we were
looking at purchases this was actually
specific
to uh to pos to your vendors and what is
coming in
uh we were finding that transfers so
warehouse transfers weren't included nor
assemblies assemblies uh to be
just a refresher for anybody who's not
dealing with that that's an assembly is
when
you have to take components and assemble
them into a finished good
so we call it an assembly order so um
those are not included i believe
transfers are now always included so we
should cpos and transfer
orders and if you don't see that please
let us know um
or actually i mean i guess we could just
look at our fba location right
you should see that yeah incoming
shipments
um so yeah we should see transfers now
assemblies
we actually we did that as a
customization for for one account aidan
here because that was a we we had to use
assemblies
um as as a way i mean just
just specific to that business
that was how we had to represent
incoming stock um
it's not always the case a lot of times
i mean if you have the stock already in
your components
and then you're just assembling that
into a finished good then it's really
it's considering it one way or the other
but with this particular case we had to
actually also include the assembly
orders to get a true representation of
what's continuing to come
because the component stock was being
handled separately we weren't
we had to order the components but we
weren't tracking that stock so it wasn't
being represented
so we didn't include the assembly orders
then we were we were understating
our opening by picture and our our
incoming
stock so it just depends a bit on your
business um
but assemblies and variants are going to
be you know
we're still looking at all that all that
can be pointed within categories
we're considering those on the same
level so
um it's going to apply regardless
you you know you're going to get your
open to buy number whether it's by
category or by vendor and then you'll be
able to
then drill in to the next section
which actually yeah let's just pop over
there because that's really going to be
the next main area to go anyway
so we talked about that edit forecast
area i'm going to jump back there
remember we rolled up by category or now
if you do buy vendor or by brand
that's one thing we'll need to test too
to see if this function is going to work
by vendor by brand
um we we've added this feature recently
and we talked about it earlier on the
call so let's say you know we put in all
those planned revenue goals for the
ladies category
well we can go to edit forecasts i could
select that category
and we can use that bulk actions button
to seed
the planned revenue in from our open to
buy plan i'm going to do it for my i
from our ip test plan
so it's 10 higher from the prior year
we're going to take those forecasted
revenue values
we're going to they're going to be
inputted as overrides that we're going
to push
down to the variance respectively now
this is something we came across
recently
it will also consider assemblies so
assemblies or components they're all
going to be treated
we're going to look at you know how the
assemblies or the components sold
proportionately within the aggregation
so if we're looking at category
maybe 90 of your revenue actually came
from assemblies and 10 percent came from
components
because some of them sell on their own
it would be distributed accordingly
so that's what we did here with ladies
we took our
um if we go back ladies here remember
our planned revenue goals
i can even switch back to bottom up it
just makes it easier to see
you know here's those forecasted revenue
goals we came back to edit forecast
now of course once we try to push that
down if we enter a forecast revenue
here what are we doing we're trying to
we're trying to push that down to all of
the 45 variants within that category
proportionately
and doing a forecast override and then
we also need to
re-multiply by the selling price so this
is going to be very close
to what you see but not 100 percent what
what you put in
it's gonna be just slight ever so
slightly different because of the
rounding that we have to do
but that's how we can input in to say oh
okay if that's the plan
revenue we're going to override the
automatic forecast that we come up with
to use those revenue goals instead and
distribute those forecasted sales
down to the variance proportionately
based on how they've been selling in the
last two months
and it'll be the same if you were to do
it an override by vendor
we would distribute your forecast
revenue down to the 58 variants that are
part of
that supplier us aggregation so it'd be
the same kind of idea there
all right so yes it should
work just the same assemblies or
variants um that is something that we
came across
and we've tested out so all of it should
work
just the same if you do need assembly
orders considered because
your comp your incoming component stock
isn't reflected in here for any reason
then let us know we can make sure that
we capture your incoming assembly orders
to be factored in here um at the end of
the day we just need to make sure we
have an accurate picture of
what the opening stock is and what's
truly coming for that category
so we can figure out what else to
purchase all right perfect
we do have another question um danielle
is asking
um is there a way to remove inactive
items from the catalog
as a fashion store they have many of
their items that only come in one time
so they're not replenishing the exact
same item so how would we handle that in
in open dubai
um yeah i mean so open open to buy we
should be focusing here on on
variants that are replenishable so
really as as you
are coming out of the season i think
make sure you mark those variants as
non-replenishable and then they wouldn't
be reflected in here
you can always do that in whether it's
replenishment or
directly in the catalog section so if
you're in replenishment
no however it is let's say we're
grabbing items with a specific tag from
shopify
right or we're just filtering anything
that says mango
and not magno they were grabbing
everything that says mingo
and everything with this keyword uh you
know we're we're we're discontinuing was
just a seasonal item
bulk actions here set to
non-replenishable
now we wouldn't factor in these mango
products with our open divide plan so
you spark that stuff as
non-replenishable
any point all right
sounds good um yeah if
anybody has any more questions feel fr
feel free to drop them either in the
chat or the q
a section at the bottom of your zoom
window there
um basil i'm gonna
um just jump in here um before we
we start to um see people
um i know it's late in in some time
zones we're covering so
um i just want to jump in here i know
some folks are newer to inventory
planner
whether you have a new account or you're
new to your team or would like a
refresher we do
have kind of an introduction to demand
planning and inventory planner usage
webinar next week i'm going to drop in
here the registration
link um that was pinned
so i'll drop that in here feel free to
sign up join us for that as basel was
showing you down there in the
in the chat um we'll uh
we've made a note available to you so
you can um check that out we'll we'll
pop that up again this weekend um just
as a little reminder in case you're not
already signed up
um but we'd love to have you join us for
that as well
then just a blanket invitation um for
feedback if there are other topics you'd
like us to cover please let us know
probably after the first of the year
we'll get into planning for the new year
so it may be a bit on open to buy
as well as how to apply that to other
parts of your your planning and
in purchasing process but if there are
other topics you'd like us to get into
definitely let us know we want to make
sure these are relevant to
your situation kind of the challenges
you're facing and and hopefully that
they're
they're useful to you as well so that's
uh that's my little interlude
jumping in on uh future sessions here
yeah
um yeah i i'd love to touch on a couple
other things now again please jump in
with questions as you have them
um one thing i want to mention you can
always adjust the period you're looking
at for your plan up here in the top
right
if you want to look say you just want to
focus on the next six months you want
like the next 12 months whatever that
might be
so you can always adjust the time period
that you're looking at
um you're also going to notice if if you
you know if you try if you don't enter
some information
you would notice errors also um
so for example let me go back to my ip
test
plan um
we get errors here actually call this
one
test there's some errors actually show
up as soon as you create a plan because
if you don't put in any planned revenue
then we can't really do any analysis
so keep an eye also you'll see like a
red a
little alert button that'll kind of give
you a sense of hey we can't
you know we cannot give you a a
recommendation with this plan to cover
if we don't have planned revenue in
these upcoming months sometimes if you
seed your revenue for example
from the prior year it'll do it for the
next 12 months
but then we won't see the revenue beyond
that so if it stays at zero and then you
try to put a high cover
um you know let's say i try to put in
like one month or anything here well
let's
we can't um
a little toolbar for some reason that
gets caught sometimes here
did it give us an error ah it actually
didn't
interesting yeah it usually will we
don't have a revenue
well instead in this one it's just
recommending we don't really buy
anything
i guess because we have some pos that
are coming in this particular case
yeah so but you'll you should pay
attention to it we i i definitely have
noticed it when we
kind of especially when you plant yeah
when you input your plan to revenue
but then that revenue only goes into a
certain point and then you try to put in
a stock cover goal
and the system isn't really sure how to
handle it
so maybe like we have 10 000 for these
upcoming months or something
whatever it might be actually we'll say
even higher
and then you know if i'm trying to do
some really high cover
oops 10 months of cover or anything
well we can't like we don't have all the
information here that we that we need
for this to work so we're gonna we're
gonna see some errors in this case
so yeah it's invalid we have to set the
revenue for for may
because that's 10 months from now so
that's
those are the kind of errors to pay
attention to um in terms of checking the
data you see i want to also
just touch on that because we get a lot
of questions about this
um if i go back to my ip test this will
say you know you're trying to just
understand how are we getting this
opening stock number
how do we get this actual revenue number
for november
um sales so far right if we're ever
trying
or how just like we saw with the
purchases and and how we can make sense
of that and the purchase order delivery
schedule
and we can check it out if we're trying
to see by category or by vendor
how are we actually coming up with the
pos at retail uh
at retail value at cost in units
sure you know so that's that's how you
can always double check
what's what's coming and when and you
could always come into purchase orders
directly and see
you know use your filters to focus on
pos that are coming
yeah you know i would say with an
expected date
um we could say if you want to see
within the month of november and like
really focus in on on these specific pos
and this would give you a sense of
what's showing up in in that metric but
i would
especially for anything with opening
stock planned revenue etc
reports kpi report this is a really
critical area to really understand
why you're seeing what you see if i'm in
my combined warehouse let's say i go to
categories
and i want to see for ladies let's say i
want to focus on
november right that wasn't you know that
that's a month that's really key for us
to understand right now
stock stock cost stock retail
always based on today which is november
11th
all right if i want to get a sense of my
stock position on november 1st
you can come to you can add the columns
to your kpi report
search opening you can do opening or
closing stock it's going to be driven
off of that date range selector so if i
want to get a sense of what my opening
stock
cost and retail was as of november 1st
we can add those columns in
now as many of you know we can always
reorder where those columns are i'll
just leave them where they are and drag
over to the right
these values would represent our stock
at retail
so this would be our opening stock at
retail for the ladies category as of
november 1st
for 301 000 so let's go compare 301
000 um opening the month of november
it's actually very very very slightly
different
which i'm curious why that would be the
case so that would be something that we
can kind of go and check
so we said dresses says 856
791 you know 856 and
it's super close super
close slightly different
that could be just the time of the day
could be that it's our demo store
typically it's going to match match up
but there could be
some different reasons as to why we see
that this is where we can go
to spot check that data of course we can
also grab any time frame up here
and just check sales revenue generated
profit margin cost of goods sold there's
ah there's over 180 metrics you can add
to these tables
if you're ever curious you can always
grab that widget at the bottom right
check the glossary of terms and just see
what's kind of baked into that metric
definitely a really useful place to go
just to understand what you look at the
data that you're looking at
a lot of times if you're ever seeing
something kind of wonky especially in
terms of your opening stock or purchases
i found especially like let's say you
have gift cards
with a an arbitrarily high retail price
um something like that or or maybe you
put in a million
in stock because it doesn't really
matter those
those are the things to be careful with
i would definitely tuck anything like
that
in in a category that we can go and hide
easily and
whether it's a miscellaneous or an
unknown category then we can come over
to actions category organizer
get that stuff out of here because it's
going to throw off our plan completely
but that's how i definitely recommend
spot checking that data
maybe you see that there's some super
super high number for opening stock in a
specific category
and come back here and say oh wow why
are we getting stock retail of
95 million then we can click into the
specific variants and see what is drive
which one is actually driving that
we can come in and um you know we can we
can sort by any particular column to
make sure we get the information
uh yeah i just want to make sure to talk
about that that piece of spot checking
some of the data that you're seeing in
here because
it has a direct impact on the
recommendations of course
do we have any other questions yep
ricardo has a question
he says how would you do otb planning
when you
your categories your vendor your brand
clusters are not what you're wanting to
use
for the projected sales any options to
cluster by tag
or a different workaround
as it is today unfortunately not um
there's yeah it's it was all
historically it's always only been
by category and as of now it's with
vendor
and by brand um but that's that's the
extent of it
um maybe now you can assign
variants to multiple vendors thinking
through this
so if you're if you're using inventory
planner to configure vendors
or even if you're not let's say you have
like a dummy vendor
that should work really yeah i mean if
you have like a cluster
one vendor and even if that like you
have variants
that you want to add as part of that
cluster so you sign all of them with
that vendor
and you can assign them to your other
vendor for your normal purchasing they
would still be considered there
but then when you actually go to
associate it you would see it with if
you were to create an open to buy plan
by vendor then you could focus on
that cluster uh that cluster vendor
instead
um to that point one really really
really important piece
that i glossed over uh is is making sure
that the subsets you're looking at if
we're looking at categories vendors or
brands however you're building your plan
should be mutually exclusive if it's not
then you're going to notice especially
the total values are not going to make
sense
we'll notice this especially because we
we don't see for example subcategories
we see categories only so if you have a
system that has categories and
subcategories they're going to show up
separately
and they would be reflected twice at the
top level in that case i would come to
actions
category organizer and only select
either categories or subcategories so
that it's all mutually exclusive
you could plan for any specific category
any specific subcategory
or any vendor like the cluster vendor
and they're assigned to another vendor
if you don't have mutually exclusive
categories vendors brands etc
i would definitely not do a top-down
plan um it would give you it would give
you some strange behaviors unless you
really hone in on your category
organizer
so that whatever you have in here is
mutually exclusive if it's not
definitely handle it at a bottom-up
level to make sure that it's accurate
awesome i think that's all the questions
that we have
in right now if we're winding down on
time so if you have any lingering
questions
either drop it in the chat or q a or um
you know
chat with us down in that that widget in
the lower right hand corner
we're glad to talk with you set up some
time to kind of talk through your otv
plan if you have lingering questions um
so i think that we're kind of wrapping
up unless you have any uh
lingering uh additional nuggets of
information you wanna
share with us basil squeezing
i feel like open to buy it's a lot to
absorb at first and a lot of it is just
going to come down to experimentation
like i said it's very different for
every business um and
yeah maybe maybe you'll find we
shouldn't include transfers in your case
i mean whatever whatever that looks like
you know i definitely encourage you to
jump in
don't be shy to create different plans
this is a
it's a planning environment what you do
in here has no
direct impact on forecasting and
replenishment unless you take the
information
and go to edit forecast and seed that
information back in
so it's consider it a playground you can
create different plans and you can just
kind of test it out see what the data
looks like
and how to set it up in a way that
you're going to draw meaning from it
i would definitely just just poke around
include some of your other metrics
get a sense of of how all this is
looking and
um i guess i didn't really touch on the
especially if you if you used to use
open to buy with inventory planner and
then you're kind of returning to it
one really key thing that i should
mention that has changed
uh is spot cover versus forward cover
everything we talked about today you're
gonna notice we've been do
you plan on forward cover to say you
know yeah you want to enter
february with enough to cover you for
the next two months well it would look
at your coverage for
february and march so it's a much more
straightforward way of looking at it
historically it was different and and
what i mean by that is
is like let's say in in december you had
one and a half million it's
way higher and then it has a massive
drop off in
january these months are only going to
be 200 000.
all right i'm going to save this in
oh actually i don't want to lift my
forward cover up a bit
sticking that all in so the difference
here
this this method in general is going to
make a lot more sense um
and actually the spot cover calculation
doesn't even look like it's doing what
it used to do anymore
typically spot cover we would look at
the planned revenue
um oh actually that's because yeah i see
what's going on here yeah let's say
let's say i buy
three months worth okay so remember what
we've talked about for december
we want to with this type of information
in here it's going to say
let's look at 1.9 million um it's gonna
make sure
that we enter the month of
december with 1.9 million which is which
is enough to cover us for three months
with one half and then so we need about
1.9 million which makes sense
so it says okay that's what we need all
of this in mind was selling a ton
in december and we closed the month of
december with 408 000.
well in terms of ford cover that leaves
us with a couple months
spot cover is always going to be based
on the goal for that month so if we're
realizing you know it's actually only
going to sell 10 000 let's say it's
going to be a massive drop-off
spot cover would go way higher because
it's only looking at
the planned revit it's like only looking
at this month and saying oh wow
you know opening stock of 218 000 versus
a 10 000 revenue
goal that's 21 months of cover based on
only this month
that's the way it used to be planned in
our system which is which is more
confusing
so to any of our existing users who are
coming back
just just keep in mind how much more
useful
it is to do with this forward cover
method again this just
nudged up just a little bit because we
had existing pos but in general it's
like
you want to maintain three months of
cover great no problem you know we could
just kind of
have threes across the board um and
we're always going to be looking at the
current month and the next couple months
uh in that case so you can kind of keep
it flat
rather than sort of trying to back into
that with that spot cover
um yeah just another little tidbit to
any of our existing users
now those are all the main tidbits i
have it's i know like i said it's a lot
to take in so please poke around
let us know what feedback you have as
you have questions as you go along
you can of course use the resources go
to the kpi report or your po delivery
schedule report and get a sense of why
you're seeing what you see
and then also feel free to ping us down
here at the bottom right if you're
just not able to understand why you're
seeing something or you're just trying
to get the best out of the system and
you have a couple questions
don't be shy to give us to give us a
shout at that point as well
awesome all right so uh that takes us
right up to the end of our time as a
reminder you will get a link
to the recording of this within 24 to 48
hours typically um so we'll send you an
email with that definitely let us know
what questions you have
and thanks so much for for joining us
today we're really glad to
have you here and have so much interest
in open to buy
all right bye everybody take care
you